[
  {
    "subject": "Čeština",
    "theme": "Literární směry konec 19. stol"
  },
  {
    "question": "Osvobozená slova",
    "answer": "futurismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "zvlněná linie",
    "answer": "secese"
  },
  {
    "question": "J. Cocteau",
    "answer": "kubismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "kaligramy",
    "answer": "dadaismus, kubofuturismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "V. Majakovkij",
    "answer": "futurismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "květinové motivy",
    "answer": "secese"
  },
  {
    "question": "citově nadnesené vyjádření",
    "answer": "expresionismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "1909",
    "answer": "futurismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "T. Tzara",
    "answer": "dadaismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "technika",
    "answer": "futurismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "automatické texty",
    "answer": "surrealismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "S. Freud",
    "answer": "surrealismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Alkoholy",
    "answer": "kubofuturismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "poslední univerzální sloh",
    "answer": "secese"
  },
  {
    "question": "1907",
    "answer": "kubismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "P. Eluard",
    "answer": "surrealismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Kaligramy",
    "answer": "kubofuturismus, dadaismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "pásmo",
    "answer": "kubofuturismus"
  },
    "question": "1916",
    "answer": "dadaismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "1929",
    "answer": "expresionismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pásmo",
    "answer": "kubofuturismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "A. Breton",
    "answer": "surrealismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ch. Morgenstern",
    "answer": "dadaismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "A. Mucha",
    "answer": "secese"
  },
  {
    "question": "G. Apollinaire",
    "answer": "kubofuturismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "P. Picasso",
    "answer": "kubismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "F. Marinetti",
    "answer": "futurismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "V. Chlebnikov",
    "answer": "futurismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "rychlost",
    "answer": "futurismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Kabaret Voltaire",
    "answer": "dadaismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Košilela",
    "answer": "dadaismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "1924",
    "answer": "surrealismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "1910 - 1920",
    "answer": "expresionismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "šelma",
    "answer": "fauvismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Šibeniční písně",
    "answer": "dadaismus"
  },
  {
    "question": "1890 - 1900",
    "answer": "secese"
  },
  {
    "question": "asociace",
    "answer": "surrealismus"
  }
]
